<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % general-entities SYSTEM "../../general.ent">
  %general-entities;
]>

<sect1 id="ch-temp-system-choose">
  <?dbhtml filename="choose.html"?>

  <title>To Boot or to Chroot?</title>

  <para os="a"> There are two different ways you can proceed from this point
  to build the final system. You can build a kernel, a bootloader, and
  a few other utilities, boot into the temporary system, and build the
  rest there. Alternatively, you can chroot into the temporary system.</para>

  <para os="b">The boot method is needed when you are building on a different
  architecture. For example, if you are building a PowerPC system from
  an x86, you can't chroot. The chroot method is for when you are
  building on the same architecture. If you are building on, and for,
  an x86 system, you can simply chroot. The rule of thumb here is if
  the architectures match and you are running the same series kernel
  you can just chroot. If you aren't running the same series kernel, or are
  wanting to run a different ABI, you will need to use the boot option.</para>

  <para os="c">If you are in any doubt about this, you can try the following
 commands to see if you can chroot:</para>

<screen ><userinput>${CLFS}/tools/lib/libc.so.6
${CLFS}/tools/bin/gcc -v</userinput></screen>

  <para>If either of these commands fail, you will have to follow the boot
  method.</para>

  <para>To chroot, you will also need a Linux Kernel-2.6.x (having been
  compiled with GCC-3.0 or greater). The reason for the kernel version
  requirement is that, without it, thread-local storage support in Binutils
  will not be built and the Native POSIX Threading Library (NPTL) test suite
  will segfault.</para>

  <para>To check your kernel version, run <command>cat /proc/version</command>
  - if it does not say that you are running a 2.6.2 or later Linux kernel,
  compiled with GCC 3.0 or later, you cannot chroot.</para>

  <para os="e">For the boot method, follow <xref linkend="chapter-boot"/>.</para>

  <para os="f">For the chroot method, follow <xref linkend="chapter-chroot"/>.</para>

</sect1>
