<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % general-entities SYSTEM "../../general.ent">
  %general-entities;
]>

<sect1 id="ch-intro-resources">
  <?dbhtml filename="resources.html"?>

  <title>Resources</title>

  <sect2 id="ch-intro-faq">
    <title>FAQ</title>

    <para>If during the building of the CLFS system you encounter any
    errors, have any questions, or think there is a typo in the book,
    please start by consulting the Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ)
    that is located at <ulink url="&faq-root;"/>.</para>

  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="ch-intro-maillists" xreflabel="Chapter 1 - Mailing Lists">
    <title>Mailing Lists</title>

    <para>The <uri>cross-lfs.org</uri> server hosts a number of
    mailing lists used for the development of the CLFS project. These lists
    include the main development and support lists, among others. If the
    FAQ does not contain your answer, you can search the CLFS lists via
    The Mail Archive <ulink url="http://www.mail-archive.com"/>. You can
    find the mail lists with the following link:</para>

    <para><ulink url="http://www.mail-archive.com/index.php?hunt=clfs"/></para>
   
    <para>For information on the different lists, how to subscribe, archive
    locations, and additional information, visit <ulink url="&clfs-wiki;wiki/lists"/>.</para>

  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="ch-intro-newsserver">
    <title>News Server</title>

    <para>Cross-LFS does not maintain it's own News Server, but we do provide
    access via <uri>gmane.org</uri> <ulink url="http://gmane.org"/>. If you want to subscribe
    to the Cross-LFS via a newsreader you can utilize <uri>gmane.org</uri>.
    You can find the game search for CLFS with the following link:</para>

   <para><ulink url="http://dir.gmane.org/search.php?match=clfs"/></para>

  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="ch-intro-irc">
    <title>IRC</title>

    <para>Several members of the CLFS community offer assistance on our
    community Internet Relay Chat (IRC) network. Before using this support,
    please make sure that your question is not already answered in the CLFS
    FAQ or the mailing list archives. You can find the IRC network at
    <uri>chat.freenode.net</uri>. The support channel for cross-lfs is
    named #cross-lfs. If you need to show people the output of your
    problems, please use http://pastebin.cross-lfs.org and reference
    the pastebin URL when asking your questions.</para>

  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="ch-intro-mirrors" xreflabel="Chapter 1 - Mirror sites">
    <title>Mirror Sites</title>

    <para>The CLFS project has a number of world-wide mirrors to make
    accessing the website and downloading the required packages more
    convenient. Please visit the CLFS website at
    <ulink url="&clfs-wiki;wiki/mirrors"/> for mirrors of CLFS.</para>

  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="ch-intro-contactinfo">
    <title>Contact Information</title>

    <para>Please direct all your questions and comments to the
    CLFS mailing lists (see above).</para>

  </sect2>

</sect1>
