<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % general-entities SYSTEM "../../general.ent">
  %general-entities;
]>

<sect1 id="ch-bootable-grub">
  <?dbhtml filename="grub.html"?>

  <title>Making the CLFS System Bootable</title>

  <indexterm zone="ch-bootable-grub">
    <primary sortas="a-GRUB">GRUB</primary>
    <secondary>bootable</secondary>
  </indexterm>

  <para os="a">Your shiny new CLFS system is almost complete. One of the last
  things to do is to ensure that the system can be properly booted. The
  instructions below apply only to computers of x86 and x86_64 architecture,
  meaning mainstream PCs. Information on <quote>boot loading</quote> for
  other architectures should be available in the usual resource-specific
  locations for those architectures.</para>

  <para os="b">Boot loading can be a complex area, so a few cautionary words
  are in order. Be familiar with the current boot loader and any other
  operating systems present on the hard drive(s) that need to be bootable.
  Make sure that an emergency boot disk is ready to <quote>rescue</quote>
  the computer if the computer becomes unusable (un-bootable).</para>

  <warning os="w1">
    <para>The following command will overwrite the current boot loader.
    Do not run the command if this is not desired, for example, if using
    a third party boot manager to manage the Master Boot Record (MBR).
    In this scenario, it would make more sense to install GRUB into the
    <quote>boot sector</quote> of the CLFS partition. In this case, this
    next command would become <userinput>grub-install /dev/sda2</userinput>
    .</para>
  </warning>

  <para os="e">Instruct GRUB to install itself into the MBR of
  <filename class="partition">sda</filename>:</para>

<screen os="f"><userinput>grub-install /dev/sda</userinput></screen>

  <para os="c">Next, we need to generate a configuration for GRUB.
  In previous versions of grub we could create the configuration manually
  here, but with GRUB2 we can generate <filename>grub.cfg</filename>
  automatically. You can do this with the following command:</para>

<screen os="d"><userinput>grub-mkconfig -o /boot/grub/grub.cfg</userinput></screen>

</sect1>
